Guide to the International Brigades Archive, Moscow: Selected Images ALBA.PHOTO.177
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Brigades Archive, Moscow: Selected Images
1937-1938
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional
ALBA.PHOTO.177
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes, 1 binder)
This collection of images was selected from the International Brigades Archive in Moscow, Series 5: Photographs. They were originally produced in Spain by staff photographers of the International Brigades. The collection consists of copy negatives produced for and purchased by the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives in the mid-1990s. The collection includes group portraits, individual portraits and battlefield and non-combat scenes showing members and activities of the International Brigades (14th, 15th, 57th, 58th, 59th and 60th Battalions), and civilians during the Spanish Civil War. The only identified photographer is Major Vladimir Stefanovich, a Yugoslavian volunteer. Included are images of the International Brigades training, life in camp, the International Brigades Band, Spanish Republican military leaders, Communist Party leaders and distinguished visitors, including Langston Hughes, Ernest Hemingway, and Harry Pollitt.
Approximately 1,276 negatives sized from 1 7/8 x 1 1/4 inches to 2 3/4 by 4 1/4 inches
Provenance
The copy negatives making up the collection, International Brigades Archive, Moscow: Selected Images, were purchased by the Board of Governors of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives from the International Brigade Archives at the Russian State Archive of Socio-Political History (RGASPI) in 1995. This collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of ALBA collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University.
Funding for the digitization of negatives in this collection was provided by Rickard and Carol-Jeanette Jorgensen, in honor of Harry W. Randall, Jr., head of the 15th International Brigade Photo Unit, and Doreen Randall.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Historical/Biographical Note
The "International Brigades Archive, Moscow: Selected Images" is an artificial collection consisting of copy negatives made from images in the International Brigades Archive, which forms part of the Comintern Archive, housed at the Russian State Archive of Socio-Political History (RGASPI) in Moscow. The Moscow IB Archive is comprised of documents and other materials transported to the Soviet Union by Soviet authorities at the conclusion of the Spanish Civil War. Series 5 within IB Archive (Fond 545) consists of photographs taken in Spain from 1937 to 1938 by various photographers associated with the International Brigades. The only identified photographer for any of the images in this group is a Yugoslavian volunteer, Major Vladimir Stefanovich.
In the mid-1990s, as part of preparations for an ALBA-sponsored traveling photograph exhibit, representatives of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Board of Governors requested the staff at RGASPI to make a selection of images from their collection, emphasizing material relating some way to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. This selection of black and white photo prints and one presentation album of drawings, inscriptions and photos, were photographed in the Moscow archive and delivered to ALBA in the form of negative sheets.
Scope and Content Note
Among the subjects represented are group photographs and portraits of members of the International Brigades (Including British, Dimitrov, Dombrowski, Lincoln-Washington and MacKenzie Papineau Battalions), International Brigades training, life in camp, leisure activities, International Brigades Band, Spanish Republican military leaders, Communist Party leaders (including Earl Browder and Harry Pollitt), distinguished visitors such as Langston Hughes and George Orwell (Eric Blair), and a photo album compiled by Major Stefanovich prior to the Brunete offensive. Although these photographs were not the work of the unit specifically designated to record activity of the English-speaking units, there are a substantial number of images of U.S. and Canadian volunteers included. The collection also includes street scenes, wall newspapers and posters, scenes of civilians socializing with or observing IB volunteers, and a few images of Nationalist casualties. One group of images reproduces each page of a souvenir album presented to the U.S. Communist volunteers by the Communist Party of Spain.
Each file folder has a descriptive title provided by the International Brigades Archive. Basic caption information comes from an English translation of the Guide to the International Brigade Archives (Moscow) commissioned by ALBA for their own use. Some proper names have been corrected or expanded, and some abbreviations have been expanded. Many captions have been edited and expanded, and unidentified images have been provided with descriptive captions by Tamiment Library staff. Additions to the original caption list are enclosed in brackets.
Four-hundred-and-twenty-five (425) photographs are attributed to Yugoslavian volunteer, Major Vladimir Stefanovich. Folder 5 (Moscow no. 5/179) contains 195 of his photographs and folder 22 (Moscow no. 5/196) contains 230 of his photographs. The remaining 623 images are not credited to a photographer.
The negatives are printed on 5 x 7 inch sheets with 3 or 4 images per sheet.
Note to the Researcher: Only a selection of photographs from the IB collection at Moscow was copied for the ALBA archive. A comprehensive caption list of photographs in the International Brigades Archive, Moscow is available in the Tamiment Library. It comprises Series 5 of an English translation of the Russian-language guide to the International Brigades Archive, Moscow. Consult staff for access. Note, too, that all negatives from ALBA Photo 177 that were identified as being by Lincoln Brigade photographer Harry Randall and his team are not listed in this finding-aid, but are included in the finding-aid to the Randall photo collection (ALBA Photo #11). Thus, the present finding-aid does not list all negatives that are physically located in ALBA Photo 177.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged numerically according to three-part numbers assigned by the International Brigade Archives, Moscow. The three-part numbers represent series, file, and individual image numbers.
Organized in one series, arranged by image number.
Missing Title
Container list
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
ALBA Collections at the Tamiment Library.
Harry Randall: Fifteenth International Brigade Photograph Collection (ALBA Photo 11).
International Brigades Archives, Moscow: Selected Documents (microfilm)
Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Portraits.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Pictorial works; Gandesa (Spain); Jarama (Spain); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- African Americans; Ebro River (Spain); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Campaigns.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American; Russia. Rossiiskii tsentr khraneniia i izucheniia dokumentov noveishei istorii.; Negatives (photographic); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Belchite (Spain); Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional, XV; Orwell, George, 1903-1950; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Dimitrov Battalion; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Dombrowski Battalion; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; Stefanovich, Vladimir; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973; Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives
- Folder 175: Commanders of 5th Army Corps Juan Modesto, Generals Gal, Hans, Walter and Base Head Vidal Inspection of the 15th International Brigade, June 1937
  - [Officers posing on a log bridge. Eight officers and one woman. Includes Russian text.], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175001)
    General note
    Moscow Number: 5/175/1
  - [Two officers examining a document], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175002)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/2
  - [Five officers, some smoking cigarettes, one leaning on a tree], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175003)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/3
  - [Three officers in conversation, smoking], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175004)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/4
  - [Three officers in conversation. Same as 175004, but slightly different positions], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175005)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/5
  - [Two officers, man in glasses, and a woman looking at an album. Includes Klaus Becker, Henry Winkler], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175009)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/9
  - [Two officers, man with glasses, and woman looking at a letter. Watched by man with a camera. Includes Klaus Becker, Henry Winkler], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175010)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/10
  - [Two officers, man with glasses, woman looking at correspondence. Includes Klaus Becker, Henry Winkler], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175011)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/11
  - [Three officers posing], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175012)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/12
  - [Two officers smiling, third man in background], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175013)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/13
  - [Three soldiers with rifle, training (?)], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175014)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/14
  - [Soldiers with rifle, training (?)], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175015)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/15
  - [Two officers walking amongst ruined buildings], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175016)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/16
  - [On the Right, Klaus Becker (15th International Brigade Chief of Staff); Center R. Winkler (Chief of Personnel Department of the Base)], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175017)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/17
  - [Officers sitting and talking], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175018)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/18
  - [Group of officers looking at file or album. Includes Klaus Becker, Henry Winkler], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175019)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/19
  - [Officers looking at file or album. Includes Klaus Becker, Henry Winkler], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175020)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/20
  - [Officers at banquet], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175021)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/21
  - [Officers and guests at banquet. Banner in background], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175022)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/22
  - [Officers with civilians, men and women], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175023)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/23
  - [Officers speaking to a soldier in a white cap], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175024)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/24
  - [Two officers and two men, group pose], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175025)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/25
  - [Officers and men, with a woman in a dark sweater, pose in a trench], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175026)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/26
  - [Officers and visitors looking at a file or album], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175027)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/27
  - [Becker and Winkler pose in front of a truck], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175028)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/28
  - [Group at banquet table, banner in background], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175029)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/29
  - [Two officers, man with glasses, and a woman looking at an album], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175030)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/30
  - [Group at banquet table], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175031)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/31
  - [Officer sitting in a trench], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175032)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/32
  - On the Right, Klaus Becker (15th International Brigade Chief of Staff); Center R. Winkler (Chief of Personnel Department of the Base), June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175033)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/33
  - [Officers and soldiers, large group shot], June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 177_175034)
    Moscow Number: 5/175/34
- Folder 176: Harry Pollitt Visiting the 15th International Brigade, Sep 1938
  - [Harry Pollitt seated (dark jacket), with troops], Sep 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 177_176001)
    Moscow Number: 5/176/1
  - [Officers assembled in plaza], Sep 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 177_176003)
    Moscow Number: 5/176/3
  - Harry Pollitt standing among seated men, Sep 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 177_176005)
    Moscow Number: 5/176/5
- Folder 177: Commanders of the 15th International Brigade, 1937-1938
  - [Vladimir Copic, smiling portrait], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177001)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/1
  - [Two officers on horseback], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177002)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/2
  - [Vladimir Copic pose full shot], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177003)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/3
  - [Officer pose, portrait shot], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177004)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/4
  - [Vladimir Copic and officers group shot], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177005)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/5
  - [Soldier receiving an award; officers at outdoor table], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177006)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/6
  - [Vladimir Copic and six officers, group shot], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177007)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/7
  - [Six soldiers conducting exercise in brush, binoculars], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177008)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/8
  - Dave Moran (Near Huesca), 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177009)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/9
  - Robert Merriman (Quinto), 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177010)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/10
  - [Seated officer], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177011)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/11
  - Vladimir Copic and Vidal (?), [and man and woman looking at album, same group as 175009], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177013)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/13
  - Dave Doran Addressing Canadian and American Replacements (Fuentes de Ebro), 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177015)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/15
  - Klaus Becker (Lieutenant Colonel, Expelled from Spain), 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177016)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/16
  - [Officers group pose], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177018)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/18
  - Vladimir Copic and [officers group, wide shot], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177019)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/19
  - [Three officers pose], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177020)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/20
  - [Soldiers group shot on hillside], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177021)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/21
  - [Troops pose in front of building], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177022)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/22
  - [Two men in leather coats talking next to a car], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177023)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/23
  - [Two smiling soldiers], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177024)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/24
  - [Soldiers with binoculars], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177025)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/25
  - [Soldiers marching past a house with banners], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177026)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/26
  - [Robert and Marion Merriman, with officers], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177027)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/27
  - [Vladimir Copic, officers posed against a hedge], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177028)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/28
  - [Soldiers seated in brush, officers observing], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177030)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/30
  - [Soldiers seated in brush with binoculars, officers observing], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177032)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/32
  - [Officer full shot with countryside in background], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177033)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/33
  - [Vladimir Copic closeup], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177034)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/34
  - [Vladimir Copic closeup], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177035)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/35
  - [Officer and troops with Dimitrov banner], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177036)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/36
  - Klaus Becker, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177038)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/38
  - [Copic and officers pose near a fence], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177039)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/39
  - Three officers pose, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177040)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/40
  - [Soldiers with Dimitrov banner], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177041)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/41
  - [Three soldiers in town], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177042)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/42
  - Vladimir Copic (Center) [with group of students], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177043)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/43
  - [Four officers with woman, wide shot in front of a destroyed building], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177045)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/45
  - [Two officers in front of a doorway], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177046)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/46
  - [Copic and another officer in front of wall], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177047)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/47
  - Vladimir Copic [with large group of soldiers and civilians], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177048)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/48
  - [Man in 3/4 profile against sky], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177049)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/49
  - [Man with two soldiers. Same individual as 177049], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177050)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/50
  - [Copic in profile against hedge], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177051)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/51
  - [Copic portrait], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177052)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/52
  - Bill Alexander (receiving Award for Distinguished Action at Quinto and Belchite), 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177053)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/53
  - 15th International Brigade Staff Meeting (Ebro Front), 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177054)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/54
  - [Copic portrait mid shot], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177055)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/55
  - Dave Doran, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177056)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/56
  - [Helmeted troops pose with officer], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177057)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/57
  - [Officers participating in outdoor exercise, swing from pole], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177058)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/58
  - [Vladimir Copic, mid shot], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177059)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/59
  - Vladimir Copic, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177060)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/60
  - Estado Mayor, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177061)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/61
  - Last 15th International Brigade Staff Members, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177062)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/62
  - [Radio equipment operation], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177063)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/63
  - [Two officers and man, smiling pose], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177064)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/64
  - [Copic and three officers pose], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177065)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/65
  - [Vladimir Copic and two officers], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177066)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/66
  - [Soldiers standing in fron of Dimitrov banner], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177067)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/67
  - [Vladimir Copic and another officer], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177068)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/68
  - [Large group shot with weapons, in front of stone wall], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177069)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/69
  - [Copic and woman on a beach], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177070)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/70
  - [Vladimir Copic by sandbag wall], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177071)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/71
  - [Copic closeup], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177072)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/72
  - [Copic reading Pravda], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177073)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/73
  - [Officers meeting outdoors, woman at left], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177074)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/74
  - Smercka, Vladimir Copic, Klein [with others], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177075)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/75
  - Vladimir Copic (Right) [with officers and soldiers sitting on the ground], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177076)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/76
  - Vladimir Copic (Right) [with same group as in 177076], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177077)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/77
  - [Vladimir Copic (Right), soldiers seated around him], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177078)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/78
  - [Copic closeup], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177079)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/79
  - [Soldier playing mandolin and singing with group], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177080)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/80
  - Vladimir Copic, Smercka, Klein [and others], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177081)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/81
  - [Vladimir Copic reading magazine], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177082)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/82
  - [Copic gathered with other officers around table], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177083)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/83
  - Alan Johnson (Last on Left) [with soldiers and civilians], 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 177_177084)
    Moscow Number: 5/177/84
- Folder 178: Undated Photographs
  - [Troops standing in an open plaza], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178001)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/1
  - [Soldiers relaxing in a trench, reading documents (letters?)], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178002)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/2
  - [Soldier working at a bench with slide-rule and rolled-up documents], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178003)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/3
  - [Crowd of men, close-up view], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178004)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/4
  - Slavonivitch (Chief of Information at Jarama and Brunete), Sterling Rochester, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178005)
  - [Men working in a communications post, portraits of Stalin and of Dolores Ibarurri on wall], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178006)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/6
  - [Man working in a communications post, seated], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178007)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/7
  - [Soldier tunes radio and writes], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178008)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/8
  - [Soldier poses in uniform with map/chart], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178009)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/9
  - [Soldiers, three at front of group with musical instruments], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178010)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/10
  - [Soldiers in trench, one giving another a haircut], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178011)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/11
  - [Man posed by sandbags], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178012)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/12
  - [Troops seated by a cliff with weapons], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178013)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/13
  - [Officer addressing troops in a field], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178014)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/14
  - [Camp setup (a lean-to), soldiers relaxing], undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 177_178015)
    Moscow Number: 5/178/15